okay we're going over Ben Bruno's top
four favorite landmine
exercises uh we've gone over the single
leg ardio we've gone over the reverse
lunge and we've gone over the squat and
now to finish off the fourth video is
going to be the deadlift he's going to
show you two different ways to utilize
the line land mine with the
deadlift okay I want to go over two ways
to use the land mine to dead the first
is actually very similar to a kettle
bell sumo deadli where you hold the
kettle bell between your legs only here
you're going to use the land mine in a
similar fashion to take advantage of the
AR of the bar with a slight path
backwards to create more of a posterior
weight shift and put more stress in the
glutes so you're going to stand up with
a stance slightly wider than shoulder
width interlock your fingers like this
to help with grip strength chest up grab
right underneath the bar come up and
then set up with the bar right in front
of your body from there you're going to
basically do like you would do with a
kettle bell
deadli back posterior weightp and
forward so there's a slight KNE Bend and
the hip hands
back the second variation is the land
line remaining in dead exact same
starting position so I won't go over
that only difference here is that
there's little to no knee flexion I like
to tell people that the legs are
straight but not lock
so there all you're going to do is tell
people to keep their chest up and bump
straight back so interlock your fingers
bar right here
here here you're going to feel a big
stretch in your hands here some people
will go all the way to the floor some
people will just go to the knee or even
slightly above and I'm fine with either
way main thing here is that you keep a
nice neutral lower back gets back back
you feel a slight stretch in your
hamstrings come through and squeeze your
glutes at the top so those are the two
ways to use the land line together